<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docs on Computable Spec</title>
    <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docs on Computable Spec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/attacks/</guid>
      <description>Attacks This section catalogs known attacks on the protocol and known defenses against such attacks.
Front Running Attacks In the current version of the protocol, it is possible for a determined adversary to front-run a number of protocol interactions. For example, if a listing with a given listingHash is proposed but not yet confirmed as a transaction, the adversary could create an alternative transaction with the same listingHash to attempt to block the original listing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/capi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/capi/</guid>
      <description>The Computable API We&amp;rsquo;ve covered the core Computable contracts at some depth in the last few chapters. However, we haven&amp;rsquo;t said too much detail about the datatrust. We&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned briefly that the datatrust is a key-value store that holds data off-chain. What else is a datatrust responsible for doing? When is some piece of software a datatrust? In particular what are the external signals and messages thata datatrust must respond to?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/continuing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/continuing/</guid>
      <description>Continuing Your Journey Congrats on making it through the entire Computable book! You&amp;rsquo;ve come out on the other side ready to enter the Computable ecosystem and start building your own Computable data markets, libraries, and companies.
You might be now wondering how you can continue learning. As you&amp;rsquo;ve probably already realized, there&amp;rsquo;s a vast amount of material required to understand Computable from the bottom up. The system touches upon economics, systems software, blockchains, cryptography and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/contracts/</guid>
      <description>The Computable Contracts In this chapter , we&amp;rsquo;ll briefly review the smart contracts that form the core of the Computable protocol. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t encountered smart contracts before, you might not have a clear idea of what they are. Briefly put, they are programs that run on the Ethereum blockchain. You might ask, why is this important? How is it different from just running a program on the cloud? The main difference is that smart contracts run in duplicate on every one of the thousands of nodes that constitute Ethereum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/datatrust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/datatrust/</guid>
      <description>The Datatrusts A Datatrust is a software system that is responsible for storing data and coordinating with on-chain permissions layers. Put another way, the Datatrust is the off-chain portion of the Computable protocol, responsible for storing data, and delivering it upon purchase.
Each data market maintains an authorized Datatrust on-chain. A stakeholder vote is needed to authorize or remove a datatrust.
Datatrust Implementation Specification A Datatrust is a system that is responsible for storing data off-chain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/ethertoken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/ethertoken/</guid>
      <description>Ether Token The first point of entry into the Computable ecosystem is the EtherToken contract. This contract is simply a wrapper for ETH that gives it an ERC-20 interface. You will need EtherToken for all your interactions with the Computable smart contracts.
To get started, you need to call the EtherToken.deposit() function and deposit some ETH
@public @payable def deposit(): &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot; @notice Facilitate a user purchasing EtherToken with Eth at a 1:1 ratio &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot; self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/listings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/listings/</guid>
      <description>Listings A data market holds a set of &amp;ldquo;listings&amp;rdquo;. Each listing corresponds to a chunk of data contributed by a single maker and managed within the data market. The listing is physicaally stored
off-chain in the datatrust for this market.
We reproduce the fields of the on-chain listing structure (in Listing.vy) below.
struct Listing: owner: address supply: wei_value  Let&amp;rsquo;s take a minute to walk through the fields of this struct to explain how the Listing works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/markettoken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/markettoken/</guid>
      <description>Market Token MarketToken is a mintable and burnable ERC-20 token (we&amp;rsquo;ll say more on what those terms mean soon). The MarketToken is tied to a particular data market and is created when the data market is created. What is the purpose of MarketToken? Well simply put, the MarketToken corresponds to &amp;ldquo;shares&amp;rdquo; in a dataset. In everyday life, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably bought share in companies. These shares give you some rights. You can vote on some company decisions, and have rights to some portion of the company&amp;rsquo;s wealth (albeit in limited form).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/parameters/</guid>
      <description>Market Parameters The data market is governed by a set of a parameters dictated within Parameterizer. These parameters govern the function of the market by setting various critical settings. These parameters can be modified via a stakeholder vote. Let&amp;rsquo;s review the parameters controlled in Parameterizer:
stake: wei_value  The stake (in MarketToken wei) needed to issue a challenge to a listing. This parameter is of type wei_value
vote_by: timedelta  The time (in seconds) that a poll should remain open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/reserve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/reserve/</guid>
      <description>Reserve The Reserve is the &amp;ldquo;bank account&amp;rdquo; tied to each data market. It holds the funds tied to that data market and serves as incentive for makers to contribute the market.
Think of the reserve as holding earnings from the data in the data market that belong to all the MarketToken holders associated with the market. These earnings can come from either data purchase payments or from patron support for MarketToken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/userjourney/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/userjourney/</guid>
      <description>The scope of this page is to list the user-signed contract method calls required to fulfill various user actions.
First, user-originated contract method calls must be signed by the user’s private key, which means the user probably confirms signing through a Metamask dialog.
Second, contract method calls are asynchronous and may take an indefinite amount of time since they only complete when 1 (or really several) blocks are mined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://computablelabs.github.io/compspec/docs/voting/</guid>
      <description>Voting As we&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned previously, MarketTokens are analogous to company shares. Just as company shareholders can vote on some company decisions, MarketToken stakeholders are allowed to vote on some data market governance questions. In fact, all major decisions in the data market are made by token holder vote. These decisions include which new listing candidates (a &amp;ldquo;listing candidate&amp;rdquo; is a chunk of data which has not yet been confirmed as a listing in the market) should be confirmed as listings, which challenged listings should be removed from the market (we&amp;rsquo;ll say more about challenges later), what changes should be made to the Parameterizer parameters (which govern the market&amp;rsquo;s behavior; more on this later), and who the datatrust operator should be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>